MIKE MACKENZIE

BinfoTech

mike@veb.co.nz

SKILLS

PHP, MySQL, HTML and Linux (using tools such as: vim, cron, memcache).	8 years
E-commerce solutions, including usage of 3rd party payment APIs (PayPal, PayByCash, ShareIt and DPS)	6 years
Development and release of web and desktop based solutions, including marketing before and after release	3 years
Linux server management (sys-admin)	6 years
C# application development and ASP .NET development	1 year
Python to create server-management scripts and stable web-applications. (Django web application framework, and Flask)	2 years
Javascript and jQuery in web-development	4 years
Git and GitHub for source-control. (learned Git before GitHub was released)	7 years
C development (game engine backends)	
Bugzilla for bug reporting and contributing to various open source projects	

CPM

Revenue generation for a product, or website using advertising methods such as CPA and

Have built efficient and scalable websites supporting high load and traffic within a budget to maximise revenue.

Expert experience in social media, including paid advertising campaigns in Facebook and various successful marketing campaigns. Helped various non-profit organizations in IT consulting, including web development and server administration.

EXPERIENCE

veb limited

http://veb.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand October 2014 - Present

Software Developer / Managing Director

We provide software and prototype hardware solutions to anyone. Our specialities include mobile development (for any platform), social media/community integration, desktop applications (OS X, Windows), custom server side software (sockets, SMS, backups, logging) and hardware prototypes using Arduino and Tessel.

Already under our belt has been some extremely notable achievements. One of the proudest was working with Teespring which is a YCombinator company, with \$56 million of funding achieved - and we worked closely with them in their early days. Very recently, under a great time constraint we managed to not only go far and beyond what the client thought was possible, but we delivered two great products ahead of time.

The Logic Studio

http://www.logicstudio.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand July 2014 - October 2014

Software Developer

Full-time position

Web Application development, heavy on JavaScript, with PHP5, jQuery, Angular, Bootstrap3. Responsive Web Development, heavy on "mobile-first".

University of Otago

http://www.otago.ac.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand 2012 - 2014 (2 years, 6 months)

Senior Web Developer / Applications Programmer for <u>Web Services</u>

Full-time position

Developed multiple small and large scale projects primarily developed using PHP+MySQL using the CodeIgniter Framework (LAMP stack), while learning Laravel for when our servers upgrade to PHP5.3. Used Git and GitLab for source control. Developed and supported websites using Oracle 10g CMS and Oracle DB. Created and maintained E-Commerce websites for conferences, merchandise, enquiries and forms.

Administered and supported the high-volume University Help Desk for issues and concerns related to the University CMS. Founding member of the University's Social Media Advisory Group.

The Captioning Working Group

http://www.captionitnz.co.nz/?p=195

Remote part-time work (volunteer) 2014 - 2014 (1 year)

Web Developer / System Administrator / Social Media Marketing / Consultant

For the <u>CaptionItNZ</u> campaign. I helped set up their new website, blog, Facebook Page, and Twitter account. I spent countless hours progressing it to the point where I could hand it over to the other team members,

<u>CaptionItNZ</u> was told that implementing caption support for TVNZ On Demand could cost millions of dollars and thousands of man hours, which led me to developing a very quick proof of concept https://pleasecaption.me/example (demo)

South Link Health

http://www.southlink.co.nz

Dunedin, New Zealand 2011 - 2012 (1 year)

Programmer/Analyst in the New Zealand Health Care industry.

Full-time position

Developed and maintained legacy code in C# ASP.NET web applications as well as designing and developing front-ends in jQuery, CSS and HTML5. Created and maintained production websites using Microsoft IIS server 6 and 7. Designed and developed web applications for Microsoft Reporting Services as well as web reports using jQuery charting libraries such as Flot and Highcharts.

Did rapid web application development and used various version control systems for source code control (Git + GitLab, Tortoise, CVS and Mercurial). Scoped projects developed using Agile Methodologies.

Nabi Studios

Singapore

<u>http://www.nabistudios.com</u> 2006 - 2010 (part-time remote and on-site Singapore)

Software Developer / Community Manager

Primary role was to direct and implement all web solutions and operations for an international game with 40,000 active players. Developed and maintained a virtual economy based on microtransactions for Nabi Studio's flagship game, including product promotions and item creation. Developed and implemented international payment systems to support the virtual economy.

Maintained the dedicated Linux servers used to host the game to ensure no downtime and damage control if necessary. Built and maintained scalable and efficient websites with large traffic by using different servers for database, memcache and static file hosting to ensure fast speeds and flexibility Performed database administration via MySQL+memcached and also developed and maintained C++ game server backends.

Build and cared for the game community which numbered to over 800,000 members and supervised community staff to ensure a better online experience for members. This also included building a social media presence via Youtube, Facebook and Twitter and game blogs.

EDUCATION

Otago Polytechnic

Dunedin, New Zealand

Bachelor of Information Technology

2007 - 2010

Notable achievements

- Best papers: Operating Systems (Linux) and PHP
- ODT (Otago Daily Times) award at graduation

Kings High School

Dunedin, New Zealand

2006

WEB PRESENCE

GitHub page: https://github.com/veb
GitHub gists: https://gist.github.com/veb
LinkedIn: http://www.linkedin.com/in/vebbed